

Elisabeth Strunk

Back-End Web Developer | Master of Engineering

Dublin, Ireland

@

elisabeth.maria.strunk@gmail.com

(1)

UTC+00:00

 \bigoplus

<u>elisabethstrunk.me</u>

German (native) English (fluent)

linkedin.com/in/elisabeth-strunk/

github.com/ElisabethStrunk

About Me

I am an award-winning software engineer who loves tricky back-end challenges. I have long-term remote-working experience and was part of diverse and intercultural teams. Having worked in sales, I have a proven record of my talent to effectively communicate with a host of different stakeholders including customers and colleagues. I am an ultrafast learner and a fighter, who gets things done and knows how to deliver even under highly challenging circumstances.

Competencies

Back-End	Front-End	Relational Databases	API	Deployment	Workflow
Python	HTML / CSS	SQL	Development	Bash / Shell	Continuous Integration (CI)
C / C++	JavaScript	SQLite / PostgreSQL	REST / RESTful	Linux	Automated Testing
Flask	Angular	SQLAlchemy	WebSocket	Apache	Git
			OAuth	AWS Lightsail	Scrum

Education

- Master of Engineering | University of Applied Sciences Rosenheim | Rosenheim | 03/2016 06/2018
- Bachelor of Engineering | <u>University of Applied Sciences Rosenheim</u> | Rosenheim | 10/2008 03/2013
- Basic Studies in Psychology | University of Salzburg | Salzburg | 10/2006 03/2008

Professional Experience

Software Engineer | SALT AND PEPPER Software GmbH & Co. KG | Hamburg | 07/2018 - 10/2019

I developed, tested, documented and deployed back-end and full-stack applications, working with distributed teams in an agile development environment (mainly Scrum). I did code reviews and wrote unit and integration tests for our CI.

- developed a high-speed data transfer solution sporting a custom Linux distribution, and a Python/Flask web app
 with an SQLite database, and RESTful and WebSocket APIs, surpassing customer specifications by 250%
- integrated a challenging third-party API into an application to update Docker containers running on an IoT device
- reduced front end (Angular) testing time by 90% by taking the initiative to write a test server using Python/Flask to mock a slow back end application

Software Engineering Intern | GIGATRONIK München GmbH | Munich | 09/2017 - 05/2018

I designed and implemented a modular embedded controller software in C++ for an autonomous car-like robot.

- won the prestigious VDE award (VDE e.V. is one of Europe's largest technical-scientific associations) for my work
- delivered on time, despite of important stakeholder and code contributor unexpectedly leaving the company

Technical Sales Engineer | Kieback&Peter GmbH & Co. KG | Rosenheim | 06/2013 - 03/2016

I gained a deep understanding of business processes and requirements engineering by working with a broad variety of customers and stakeholders. I managed several smaller projects, coordinating service technicians and subcontractors.

- successfully handled up to 10 projects simultaneously at times, often under time pressure
- developed an internal tool to automate technical component configuration, halving the time of offer preparations